[
    {
        "question": "The Luray Caverns can be found in which US state?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which waterfalls are between Lake Erie and Lake Ontario?",
        "answer": "Niagara Falls"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Land of 10,000 Lakes`?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the observatory where Percival Lowell first theorized the existence of Pluto?",
        "answer": "Flagstaff, Arizona"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flanders is part of which country?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which African city is famous for its native penguin population?",
        "answer": "Cape Town, South Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country can you find a beach that resembles a `golden horn`?",
        "answer": "Croatia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Toronto`s Pearson International Airport code?",
        "answer": "YYZ"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what state is the oldest winery in the United States?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to the city of Cape Girardeau?",
        "answer": "Missouri"
    },
    {
        "question": "What four US states begin with the letter `A`?",
        "answer": "Alabama, Alaska, Arizona and Arkansas"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano `Krakatoa`?",
        "answer": "Indonesia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state was named for the future James II of England?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Briton with an American wife was the governor of the Bahamas during World War II?",
        "answer": "King Edward VIII"
    },
    {
        "question": "What East Coast port is the largest US city to share its name with a British county?",
        "answer": "Norfolk, Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What California peak, which erupted in 1915, is the world`s largest lava dome?",
        "answer": "Lassen Peak"
    },
    {
        "question": "Beantown is the nickname for what US city?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many US States end with the letter N?",
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the state animal for Florida?",
        "answer": "Panther"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Valentine`s Day celebrated by having women give men chocolate?",
        "answer": "Japan and South Korea"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kazumura Cave is the longest cave in which state?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is home to the South-of-Market district?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "question": "The resort town of Avalon is situated on what California island?",
        "answer": "Santa Catalina Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "What cave found in New Mexico, is the deepest cave in the continental US?",
        "answer": "Lechuguilla Cave"
    },
    {
        "question": "Venice is well-known for its contributions to what artisanal industry?",
        "answer": "Glassblowing (It has been prevalent in Venice and the neighboring island of Murano since at least the 13th century.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What material did early Venetians use to construct the foundations of their buildings?",
        "answer": "Wood (Venice`s buildings were built on marshy mud and sand. The wood petrified due to the lack of oxygen in the marshy soil.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which famed explorer was born in Venice and now lends his name to Venice`s main airport?",
        "answer": "Marco Polo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the oldest bridge in Venice, which crosses the city`s famous Grand Canal?",
        "answer": "The Ponte di Rialto, or Rialto Bridge, was built between 1588 and 1591 to span the width of the Grand Canal."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Montevideo?",
        "answer": "Uruguay"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the country that borders Spain immediately to the its west?",
        "answer": "Portugal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capitol of Chechnya?",
        "answer": "Grozny"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country celebrates its National Day on 17th May?",
        "answer": "Norway"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest county in the United States?",
        "answer": "San Bernardino County, California"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is nicknamed the `Land of a Thousand Smiles`?",
        "answer": "Thailand"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many islands are in the so-called Thousand Islands area of the Saint Lawrence River?",
        "answer": "1,864"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s largest national park?",
        "answer": "Northeast Greenland National Park"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city will you find Le Bourget Airport?",
        "answer": "Paris, France"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Canadian city is know as `Steeltown`?",
        "answer": "Hamilton, Ontario"
    },
    {
        "question": "Boise is the capital of which US state?",
        "answer": "Idaho"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Delaware?",
        "answer": "Dover"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ulaanbaatar is the capital of which Asian country?",
        "answer": "Mongolia"
    },
    {
        "question": "On what day does Canada celebrate its birthday?",
        "answer": "July 1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hagatna is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Guam"
    },
    {
        "question": "What separates the twin cities of Minneapolis and Saint Paul?",
        "answer": "Mississippi River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is home to the third highest mountain peak in the US?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mississippi River flows into what body of water?",
        "answer": "Gulf of Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state`s name is derived from the Spanish words for `snow-covered`?",
        "answer": "Nevada"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US National Park is known for its geysers?",
        "answer": "Yellowstone National Park"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest lake lying completely inside Canada?",
        "answer": "Great Bear Lake"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only officially bilingual province in Canada?",
        "answer": "New Brunswick"
    }
]